[MUSIC]
I am from Orange County, California.
My mom was a school teacher for
the majority of my life.
She also went on to be assistant principal
and then became a principal herself.
During that entire time as a kid
growing up, I never had my summers.
I actually ended up spending all of
my time with my mom at her school.
Helping her with teachers who
wanted to restock their shelves, or
file away papers, or shred papers.
Some important advice that my mother
told me when I was growing up,
especially when I would go spend
time with her in her schools and
saw what her leadership style looked like.
She had, and still has this uncanny
ability to connect with people in ways
that not only make them feel seen,
but feel empowered.
And I think that is a very
powerful leadership style.
And it is something that I like to bring
to my project management role as well.
Because it allows me to make sure that
people feel like they can get things done,
but it's not just for me,
it's for a collective vision.
And the advice was deference gives you
the experience to be able to lead.
And it's important because as a project
manager, as we've said in these courses,
you're not going to know or you're not
going to have a lot of the technical or
specific domain expertise that
you need in order to create
the big meaty things that
you're trying to drive.
But as a program or a project manager,
you're kind of the leader who's supposed
to be making sure things get done, and you
work with every little piece of the pie.
So like my mom, who was a principal
worked with the custodial staff.
She worked with the PTA, she worked with
the teachers, and the teachers union,
she worked with the parents.
And she developed this great network of
people that helped her get things done.
So, I would say that was the best
advice that I've received.
My name is Emilio Garcia and
I am a responsible innovation
program manager at Google.